Minna Lederman Daniel Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Minna Lederman Daniel Collection 1896-1993 (bulk 1960-1990)
ML31.L43
Lederman, Minna
circa 20,000 items 22 containers 11 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
The collection contains correspondence, financial and legal papers, writings, clippings, and photographs belonging to Minna Lederman Daniel, an editor and writer about music and dance, and a major influence on 20th century music. She was a founding member of the League of Composers, a group of musicians and proponents of modern music. She helped launch the League’s magazine, The League of Composers’ Review (later called Modern Music), which was the first American journal to manifest an interest in contemporary composers.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Cage, John--Correspondence.; Cage, John.; Carter, Elliott, 1908- --Correspondence.; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990--Correspondence.; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990.; Cunningham, Merce--Correspondence.; Denby, Edwin, 1903-1983--Correspondence.; Hitchcock, H. Wiley (Hugh Wiley), 1923-2007--Correspondence.; Lederman, Minna--Correspondence.; Lederman, Minna.; Lederman, Minna.; Lederman, Minna. Life and death of a small magazine (Modern music, 1924-1946).; Oja, Carol J., 1953-; Oja, Carol J., 1953- --Correspondence.; Perlis, Vivian--Correspondence.; Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971--Correspondence.; Thompson, Tazewell--Correspondence.; Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989--Correspondence.; Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989.
Organizations
League of Composers (U.S.)
Subjects
Avant-garde (Music); Choreographers--United States--Correspondence; Composers--United States--Correspondence.; Dance--United States.; Modern dance--United States.; Music--United States--20th century--History and criticism.; Musicians--United States--Correspondence.; Musicology--United States.
Titles
League of Composers' review.; Minna Lederman collection, 1896-1993; Modern music (New York, N.Y.)
Form/Genre
Clippings (information artifacts).; Correspondence.; Financial records.; Photographic prints.; Programs.
Administrative Information
Provenance
The Minna Lederman Daniel Collection was acquired by the Library of Congress as a gift from Carol J. Oja on July 8, 2008.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Related Material
Researchers also may wish to consult the
Modern Music Archives
in the Library of Congress Music Division. Donated by Minna Lederman Daniel in 1975, this collection contains photographs, artwork, correspondence, and other documents pertaining to Modern Music, the magazine published by the League of Composers and edited by Lederman Daniel.
Access and Restrictions
The Minna Lederman Daniel Collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Performing Arts Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Minna Lederman Daniel (b. 17 March, 1896; d. 29 October, 1995) was a writer and editor on music and dance. She received professional training in music, dance, and drama before graduating from Barnard College in 1917. In 1923, she was a founding member of the League of Composers, a group of musicians and proponents of modern music. In February 1924, she helped launch the League’s magazine, The League of Composers’ Review, which was the first American journal to manifest an interest in contemporary composers. The magazine changed its name to Modern Music in 1925. She served as the sole editor of this magazine from its inception to its demise in late 1946. During this period, she developed the journal’s distinctive literary style and was directly responsible for bringing to readers the literary efforts of significant young composers such as Marc Blitzstein, Leonard Bernstein, Paul Bowles, John Cage, Elliott Carter, Aaron Copland, Roger Sessions, and Virgil Thomson. Equally important were articles written by scholars, critics, and European composers such as Bartók, Berg, and Schoenberg. The journal had the effect of nurturing an entire generation of composer-critics. For over two decades, Modern Music served as a major force within the international music world, chronicling the developments in concert music, jazz, musical theater, film, radio, and dance in the United States, Europe, and Latin America.
Following the demise of Modern Music, Mrs. Daniel (who wrote under her maiden name of Lederman) continued to write on music and dance. She edited the anthology Stravinsky in the Theatre (1947), and contributed articles to American Mercury, Saturday Review, The Nation, Show, Woman’s Home Companion, and other journals.
In 1974, Minna Lederman Daniel established the Modern Music Archives in the Library of Congress. In addition to the documentary archives of the magazine, which consists of correspondence, manuscripts, photographs, drawings, and set-designs, she also submitted her own material: an essay titled "Footnotes" (to the magazine’s history); biographical sketches of individuals represented in the Archive or otherwise connected to the magazine; and other materials, including unpublished photographs. In 1983 she compiled The Life and Death of a Small Magazine, a monograph published by the Institute for Studies in American Music. This compilation of articles, originally written for Modern Music by some of the twentieth century’s most celebrated composers, and combined with commentary contributed by Minna Lederman Daniel, won the ASCAP Deems Taylor Award for distinguished music criticism in 1984. In a 1983 New York Times article, Joan Peyser wrote that Ms. Lederman “probably shaped pre-World War II American music more than any single composer did.”
Scope and Content Note
The Minna Lederman Daniel Collection consists of the papers of this noted writer and editor. The date span of the collection is from 1896-1993, with the bulk of the materials dating from the 1960s to the early 1990s. The collection includes correspondence, writings, financial and legal papers, programs, periodicals, clippings, and photographs.
Included in this collection is correspondence with major figures in the fields of music, dance, and poetry. Several of these composers, choreographers, and poets were contributors to the magazine Modern Music, of which Minna Lederman served as sole editor from its beginnings in 1924 to its end in 1946. Of particular significance is the correspondence with composers Aaron Copland, John Cage, and Elliott Carter.
Organization of the Minna Lederman Daniel Collection
The Minna Lederman Daniel Collection is organized into four series:
Subject Files (Personal Names)
Subject Files (General Subjects)
Magazines
Personal Papers of Minna Lederman Daniel and other Daniel Family Members
http://lccn.loc.gov/2009543859
Container List
- Subject Files (Personal Names), (189 folders) (Boxes 1-12, 21)
  Contains articles, biographical materials, clippings, correspondence, discographies, notes, photographs, programs, writings, and other miscellaneous materials for named individuals.
  Arranged alphabetically by individual then type of material, and chronologically therein.
  - Albee, Edward
    - Clippings (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Anderson, Laurie
    - Clippings (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Ashbery, John
    - Clippings (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Balanchine, George
    - Clippings (Box-folder 1/4-5)
    - Correspondence (1965) (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Miscellaneous publications (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Notes (Apollo - Raymonda) (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Notes (Serenade - Waltz Academy) (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Notes (Miscellaneous) (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Programs (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Barber, Samuel
    - Clipping; Program (1958) (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Bernier, Rosamond
    - Clippings; Correspondence (1982-1984) (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Bernstein, Leonard
    - Catalog; Clippings; Program (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Blitzstein, Marc
    - Articles authored by Lederman: "Memories of Marc Blitzstein," "Marc Blitzstein Remembered," 1964 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Article authored by Oja: "The Cradle Will Rock and Mass-Song Style of the 1930s," 1989 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 1/17)
    - Correspondence - Eric A. Gordon; related papers (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Marc Blitzstein Collection: Multmedia Edition Research Grant sheet (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Program (1964) (Box-folder 1/20)
  - Boulanger, Nadia
    - Clippings (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Boulez, Pierre
    - Clippings (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Correspondence (1976-1981) (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Notes (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Programs (Box-folder 2/5)
    - 1986 U.S. Tour: Clippings (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Bowles, Paul
    - Article authored by Lederman: "The Moroccan Connection," 1980 (Box-folder 2/7)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Correspondence (1979-1991) (Box-folder 2/9)
    - Notes (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Cage, John
    - MusikTexte 46/47, Serial containing Cage memorial articles. (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Article authored by Lederman: "Farewell to John," 1992 (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Article authored by Lederman: "A View of My Own," related correspondence with Jonathan Brent (1981-1982) (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Correspondence, Relates to BBC documentary: An Inventor of Genius - John Cage; includes text. (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Catalog: Musical Works (Edition Peters); Exhibition brochure: Score and Prints Exhibition, Philadelphia, PA, 1982 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 3/6-8)
    - Clippings (Obituaries) (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Correspondence (Chronological) (1964-1993) (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Correspondence (undated), Arranged in original order per Brent Reidy inventory list.; Correspondence not found on Reidy list. (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Correspondence Index (Brent Reidy, Indiana University) (2006) (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Discography by Thom Holmes, 1981 (Box-folder 4/1)
    - Documentary: I Have Nothing to Say and I am Saying It, 1990 (Box-folder 4/2)
    - Itineraries (Box-folder 4/3)
    - Laura D. Kuhn materials: Correspondence; Writings (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Notes (Pre-1980) (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Notes (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Programs (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Writings (Cage): "Anarchy Lecture," 1988; "The First Meeting of the Satie Society," undated; "The Future of Music," 1974; "I Have Nothing Planned... " (Harvard Seminar), undated (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Writings (Cage): "James Joyce, Marcel Duchamp, Erik Satie: an Alphabet,"; "Methodstructureintentin... " (Harvard Lecture), 1988; "Series re Morris Graves," 1973 (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Caltibiano, Ronald
    - Program (1986) (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Carter, Elliott
    - Clippings (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Correspondence (1971-1992) (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Notes (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Photographs (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Programs (1968-1989) (Box-folder 5/6)
  - Chanler, Theodore
    - Clipping (Box-folder 5/7)
  - Chávez, Carlos
    - Notes (Box-folder 5/8)
  - Copland, Aaron
    - Article authored by Lederman: "Aaron Copland at Seventy," 1970 (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Article authored by Lederman: "Copland - Then and Now," 1970 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Article authored by Lederman: "It's All the Same Me," 1980 (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Article authored by Lederman: "To Aaron at Eighty," [1980] (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Articles authored by Lederman: early drafts (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Biographical brochure (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Catalogs: Musical works (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Clippings (Newspapers) (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Clippings (Periodicals) (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Clippings; Correspondence related to Copland/Perlis book party, (1984) (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Correspondence (1944-1980); Correspondence (undated) (Box-folder 6/11)
    - 83rd birthday honors (Box-folder 6/12)
    - Notes (Box-folder 6/13)
    - Photograph: Inscribed photograph (11 x 14) (Box-folder 21/1)
    - Photograph: Aberdeen, August 1974 (10 x 12) (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Programs (Box-folder 6/14)
    - Writings authored by Copland: "Statement on McCarthy," 1953; Claire Reis, (undated) (Box-folder 6/15)
  - Cowell, Henry
    - Clippings (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Crumb, George
    - Clippings (Box-folder 7/2)
  - Cunningham, Merce
    - Biographical materials (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 7/4-5)
    - Correspondence (1964-1993) (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Exhibition catalog, 1974 (Box-folder 7/7)
    - Notes (Box-folder 7/8)
    - Programs (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Promotional material (Box-folder 7/10)
  - Darrell, R. D.
    - Clippings (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Book (draft): Phono-musical pioneering (Selected writings of R. D. Darrell) (Box-folder 8/2-6)
  - Denby, Edwin
    - Article authored by Lederman: "First and Last Glimpses," 1984; related correspondence (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 8/8)
    - Correspondence (1977-1984) (Box-folder 8/9)
    - Memorial service speech, (1983) (Box-folder 8/10)
    - Programs (Box-folder 8/11)
  - Foss, Lukas
    - Clippings (Box-folder 9/1)
  - Frueh, Alfred
    - Correspondence (1947-1950) (Box-folder 9/2)
  - Gershwin, George
    - Program (1990) (Box-folder 9/3)
  - Glass, Philip
    - Clippings (Box-folder 9/4)
  - Haggin, B. H.
    - Clippings (1944-1945); Correspondence (1924-1926) (Box-folder 9/5)
  - Harris, Roy
    - Clipping (Box-folder 9/6)
  - Hitchcock, H. Wiley
    - Clippings; Correspondence (1983-1990) see also Subject Files: General Subjects, Life and Death of a Small Magazine, Correspondence (Hitchcock); Subject Files: General Subjects, Music criticism, Correspondence (Hitchcock) (Box-folder 9/7)
  - Ives, Charles
    - Article authored by Lederman: "Some American Composers," 1947 (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Correspondence (Harmony Ives) (1947) (Box-folder 9/10)
  - Jacobs, Paul
    - Clipping (Box-folder 9/11)
  - Lichtenwanger, William
    - Correspondence (1965-1978) (Box-folder 9/12)
  - Lott, R. Allen
    - Correspondence (1990-1992); Writings (Lott) (Box-folder 9/13)
  - McPhee, Colin
    - Article authored by Lederman: "Colin McPhee," 1964; Biographical brochure; Clippings; Correspondence (ca. 1949-1964); Program (1982) (Box-folder 9/14)
  - Mehta, Zubin
    - Clippings; Commemorative N.Y. Philharmonic magazine, 1984 (Box-folder 9/15)
  - Moore, Douglas
    - Correspondence (1947) (Box-folder 9/16)
  - Moseley, Carlos
    - Correspondence (1985); Notes (Box-folder 9/17)
  - Nancarrow, Conlon
    - Clippings; Correspondence (1970-1993); Programs (Box-folder 9/18)
  - Oja, Carol J.
    - Correspondence (1979-1992) (Box-folder 9/19)
    - Writings (Oja): "Colin McPhee: a Composer Turned Explorer," 1984; "The Copland-Sessions Concerts and Their Reception in the Contemporary Press," (undated); "COS COB Press and the American Composer," 1988; "Marc Blitzstein's The Cradle Will Rock and Mass-Song Style of the 1930s," 1989; "Stravinsky in the Journal of Modern Music (1924-1946)," 1981 (Box-folder 9/20)
  - Perlis, Vivian
    - Clippings (Box-folder 9/21)
    - Correspondence (1975-1990) (Box-folder 9/22)
    - Oral history interviews of Minna Lederman, conducted by Vivian Perlis, Oct. 25, 1972; Mar. 21, 1979 (Box-folder 9/23)
  - Peyser, Joan
    - Clippings; Correspondence (1974-1982) (Box-folder 9/24)
  - Reich, Steve
    - Clippings; Program (1980) (Box-folder 9/25)
  - Rieti, Vittorio
    - Clippings (Box-folder 9/26)
  - Rorem, Ned
    - Clippings (Box-folder 9/27)
  - Ruggles, Carl
    - Clipping (Box-folder 9/28)
  - Sacher, Paul
    - Clippings (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Satie, Erik
    - Program (1974) (Box-folder 10/2)
  - Schiff, David
    - Clippings (Box-folder 10/3)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 10/4)
    - Opera: Gimpel the Fool (Box-folder 10/5)
    - Programs (Box-folder 10/6)
    - Writings (Schiff): "Night Fantasies," 1980; "Musical Time in Elliott Carter's Night Fantasies," [1980]; "In Sleep, In Thunder: Elliott Carter's Portrait of Robert Lowell," undated; "Carter for Winds," 1980; "Carter in the 1970s," 1979; "Elliott Carter: A Mirror on Which to Dwell," 1977; "The Century May Already Be At an End," 1991 (Box-folder 10/7)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold
    - Catalog Musical Works; Clippings; Opera: Moses und Aron (Box-folder 10/8)
  - Schuman, William
    - Clippings (Box-folder 10/9)
  - Sessions, Roger
    - Clippings; Notes; Program (1982) (Box-folder 10/10)
  - Shapero, Harold
    - Clippings (Box-folder 10/11)
  - Shirley, Wayne
    - Correspondence (1975-1991) (Box-folder 10/12)
  - Siegmeister, Elie
    - Correspondence (1972); Writings (Siegmeister): "The Council of Creative Artists, Libraries, and Museums," 1971 (Box-folder 10/13)
  - Sondheim, Stephen
    - Clippings; Programs (Box-folder 10/14)
  - Stockhausen, Karlheinz
    - Program (1971) (Box-folder 10/15)
  - Stravinsky, Igor
    - Article authored by Lederman: "Brief Encounters," undated (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Article authored by Lederman: "Fleeting Glimpses - Fragments from an Unpublished memoir," undated (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Article authored by Lederman: "Igor Stravinsky 1882-1971 - A Modest Memorial," [1971] (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Article authored by Lederman: "Lunch at Virgil's, Tea at the Ambassador," 1989 (Box-folder 11/4)
    - Article authored by Lederman: "Stravinsky in the Theatre Symposium - Dance Index (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Articles authored by Lederman: Early drafts (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Catalog: Musical Works (Box-folder 11/7)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 11/8)
    - Homage to Stravinsky Collection, 1947-1949 (Collection gift to the New York Public Library, Lincoln Center Music Library), Sept. 1972 (Box-folder 11/9)
    - 1982 Anniversary events - Correspondence (Box-folder 11/10)
    - Notes (Box-folder 11/11)
    - Programs (Box-folder 11/12)
    - Stravinsky in Modern music (1924-1946), 1982 reprint - Correspondence (Box-folder 11/13)
    - Stravinsky in the theatre, Clippings (Box-folder 11/14)
    - Stravinsky in the theatre, Contracts; Business papers (Box-folder 11/15)
    - Stravinsky in the theatre. Correspondence: Arthur Berger (1947; 1972); George Balanchine (1972); Leonard Bernstein (1972); Carlos Chávez (1972); Robert Craft (1948-1949; 1972); Ingolf Dahl, via Lawrence Morton (1972); Alexei Haieff (1972); Lincoln Kirstein (1972); Paul Magriel (1949); Darius Milhaud (1972); Nicolas Nabokov (1972); Walter Piston (1972); Press: New York Philharmonic (1972); Vittorio Rieti (1972); William Schuman (1972); Louise Varèse (1972) (Box-folder 11/16)
    - Stravinsky in the theatre. 1975 Da Capo Press, Inc. edition. Correspondence: (1975-1976) (Box-folder 11/17)
    - Stravinsky in the theatre: Drafts (Box-folder 11/18)
    - Stravinsky in the theatre (Exhibition: NY Public Library - Library and Museum of the Performing Arts at Lincoln Center): Correspondence (Box-folder 11/19)
    - Stravinsky issue - Dance Index: Correspondence (1947-1953) (Box-folder 11/20)
  - Thompson, Tazewell
    - Biographical materials (Box-folder 11/21)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 11/22)
    - Correspondence (1983-1993) (Box-folder 11/23)
    - Notes (Box-folder 11/24)
    - Opera: The Second Hurricane - Aaron Copland/Edwin Denby commentaries (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Opera: The Second Hurricane - Reviews (Box-folder 12/2)
    - Opera: The Second Hurricane - Aaron Copland/Edwin Denby - text (1937 Production) (Box-folder 12/3)
    - Opera: The Second Hurricane - Sarah Caldwell (1984 Production) (Box-folder 12/4)
    - Opera: The Second Hurricane - Correspondence (Aaron Copland) (1984-1985 Production) (Box-folder 12/5)
    - Opera: The Second Hurricane - Correspondence (1985 Production) (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Opera: The Second Hurricane - Programs (1985 Production) (Box-folder 12/7)
    - Programs (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Script: The Caucasian Chalk Circle (Bertolt Brecht) (Box-folder 12/9)
  - Thomson, Virgil
    - Article authored by Lederman: (Untitled) (Box-folder 12/10)
    - Auction catalog (Sotheby's) Virgil Thomson Estate Sale (1990) (Box-folder 12/11)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 12/12)
    - Correspondence (1972-1987); Correspondence with Jay Sullivan, assistant to Mr. Thomson (1989-1990) (Box-folder 12/13)
    - Notes (Box-folder 12/14)
    - Opera: The Mother of Us All - Libretto; Program (1947); Review (1947) (Box-folder 12/15)
    - Programs (Box-folder 12/16)
    - Writings (Thomson): "A War's End," 1947 (Box-folder 12/17)
  - Tommasini, Anthony
    - Correspondence (1988-1991) (Box-folder 12/18)
    - Notes (Box-folder 12/19)
    - Writings (Tommasini) (Box-folder 12/20)
  - Tucker, Mark
    - Correspondence (1991); Writings (Tucker) (Box-folder 12/21)
  - Walker, David
    - Correspondence (1980-1990); Program (undated) (Box-folder 12/22)
  - Wuorinen, Charles
    - Clipping (Box-folder 12/23)
  - Young, La Monte
    - Clippings (Box-folder 12/24)
- Subject Files (General Subjects), (47 folders) (Boxes 13-16)
  Contains clippings, correspondence, financial papers, an Instrument of Gift document, magazines, notes, photographs, press releases, publicity, and writings.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject then type of material, and chronologically therein.
  - Baden-Baden Music Festival Program, July 25-28, 1929 (Box-folder 13/1)
  - Dance. The Ballet Society. Programs (Box-folder 13/2)
  - Dance. Clippings; Journals (Box-folder 13/3)
  - Dance. Notes (Box-folder 13/4)
  - Dance. Personalities, A-Z (Box-folder 13/5)
  - Dance. Programs (Box-folder 13/6)
  - Dance. Article authored by Lederman: "On Dancing," 1978 (Box-folder 13/7)
  - International Composers' Guild. Programs; Publicity materials (Box-folder 13/8)
  - League of Composers. Correspondence: Clare R. Reis (1944) (Box-folder 13/9)
  - League of Composers. Correspondence: Clare R. Reis (1945) (Box-folder 13/10)
  - League of Composers. Correspondence: Clare R. Reis (1946-1965) (Box-folder 13/11)
  - League of Composers. Publicity materials, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 13/12)
  - Life and Death of a Small Magazine. Correspondence, A-Z (Box-folder 14/1)
  - Life and Death of a Small Magazine. Correspondence: Financial and promotional (Box-folder 14/2)
  - Life and Death of a Small Magazine. Correspondence: H. Wiley Hitchcock (1979-1983) (Box-folder 14/3)
  - Life and Death of a Small Magazine. Correspondence (Legal): John J. Kominski, Library of Congress (1980-1984) (Box-folder 14/4)
  - Life and Death of a Small Magazine. Correspondence: Permissions (Box-folder 14/5)
  - Life and Death of a Small Magazine. Correspondence: Permissions (Photographs) (Box-folder 14/6)
  - Life and Death of a Small Magazine. Photographs (Box-folder 14/7)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (Box-folder 14/8-9)
  - Modern Music. Articles authored by Virgil Thomson (1940-1947) (Box-folder 14/10)
  - Modern Music. Clippings (1933-1947) (Box-folder 14/11)
  - Modern Music. Correspondence files: List (arranged in alphabetical order) (Box-folder 14/12)
  - Modern Music. Proposal/Resolution for a Cumulative Index to Modern Music, Feb. 3, 1947 (Box-folder 14/13)
  - Modern Music. Financial papers (1943-1945) (Box-folder 14/14)
  - Modern Music Archives at Library of Congress. Clippings (Box-folder 15/1)
  - Modern Music Archives at Library of Congress. Correspondence: Nathan R. Einhorn; John J. Kominski; Wayne Shirley; Ed Waters (Box-folder 15/2)
  - Modern Music Archives at Library of Congress. Correspondence: Photographs (Box-folder 15/3)
  - Modern Music Archives at Library of Congress. Instrument of Gift (1975); Amendment of Instrument of Gift (1980); related papers (Box-folder 15/4)
  - Modern Music Archives at Library of Congress. Photographs (A-G) (Box-folder 15/5)
  - Modern Music Archives at Library of Congress. Photographs (H-Z) (Box-folder 15/6)